Finding Aid for the George Alexander Heard Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Ford Foundation Papers
  - Newspaper Clippings - New York Times (May 1, 1980) "Rehnquist to Hear Black Panther Case" (Box 44)
  - Swan Ball Invitation (18th Annual) (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous (Programs, Post Cards (1979, 1980), Handwritten Poem, etc.) (Box 44)
  - Correspondence (Incoming) Invitation Responses, 1976,1980,1981 (Box 45)
  - Correspondence (Incoming) Invitation Responses, 1980,1981 (Box 45)
  - Correspondence (Incoming) Invitation Responses (Box 45)
  - Correspondence (Incoming) Invitation Responses (Box 45)
  - Correspondence (Incoming) Invitation Responses (Box 45)
  - Correspondence (Incoming) Andrew Heiskel Retirement Dinner (9-17-80) (Box 45)
  - Correspondence (Incoming) Professional - Chancellor Alexander Heard (Box 45)
  - Correspondence (Incoming) Professional - Chancellor Alexander Heard (1973,1979,1981) (Box 45)
  - Correspondence (Incoming) Professional - Chancellor Alexander Heard (Box 45)
  - Christmas Cards (1980,1981?) (Box 45)
  - Correspondence (Incoming) Alexander Heard's Birthday Cards (Box 45)
  - Notes/Lists (1980,1981) (Box 45)
  - Receipts (1980,1981) (Box 45)
  - Receipts (1980/1981) (Box 45)
  - Receipts (1980/1981) (Box 45)
  - Receipts (Box 45)
  - Programs (Concerts, Theater, Exhibits), 1979,1980,1981 (Box 45)
  - Programs (Concerts, Theater, Exhibits), 1980,1981 (Box 45)
  - Programs (Concerts, Theater, Exhibits), 1980,1981 (Box 45)
  - Travel Materials (Programs: Birmingham, Alabama, Georgia, New Mexico) (Box 45)
  - Newspaper(s) Clippings (Re: Chancellor Alexander Heard), 1980,1981 (Box 45)
  - Sarah Lawrence College Bulletin, September 1980 (Box 45)
  - American School of Classical Studies at Athens Newsletter, Spring 1979 (Box 45)
  - People, December 1, 1980 (Box 45)
  - The New Yorker, January 19, 1981 (Box 45)
  - Historic Preservation, November/December 1980 (Box 45)
  - Gift Catalogues (Box 45)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 45)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 45)
  - Miscellaneous (To be Sorted and Filed, 8-16-80) (Box 45)
  - Newspapers and Magazines (with pictures mostly) Re: Alexander Heard and other Heards (1-1-78) Box) (Box 46)
  - Filed, Miscellaneous (notes, lists, newspaper articles) (8-16-80) (Box) (Box 46)
  - Christmas Cards: (1952) (Box) (Box 46)
  - Christmas Cards: (1959) (Box) (Box 46)
  - Index Card File Box: Alumni and Development Additions - Christmas Card Index (Box 47)
  - Index Card File Box: Deleted Christmas Card Index (T thruXYZ) (Box 47)
  - Index Card File Box: Personal Christmas Card Index (Box 47)
  - Index Card File Box: Card File Invitations (Box 47)
  - (Unmarked) Index Card File Box (Box 48)
  - (Unmarked) Index Card File Box (Box 48)
  - Index Card File Box: Student Reference Files (Active/Inactive) (Box 48)
  - Index Card File Box: Deleted Christmas Card Index (A thru S) (Box 48)
  - (Unmarked) Index Card File Box (Green Metal Box) (Box 48)
  - (Unmarked) Index Card File Box: Periodicals indexed in the Reader's Guide, 1932-1953 (Box 49)
  - (Unmarked) Index Card File Box: Campaign Funds (Survey of MIP Literature since 1932, was done by H.A.) (Box 49)
  - (Unmarked) Index Card File Box: Interviews (South Carolina) (Campaign Funds?) (Box 49)
  - Index Card File Box: Social Invitations (Box 49)
- Fisk Board of Advisers papers (Box 50)
- Christmas cards (Box 51)
- Periodicals; 19th century session laws; card file (Box 52)
- Periodicals; plus miscellany (Box 53)
- Christmas cards (Box 54)
- Ford Foundation Future Program Planning Study, 1976; Christmas cards, 1952, 1953, 1967, 1971 (Box 55)
- Christmas cards, 1954, 1956; card file, desk calendar 1942; 6 mailings of printed matter form G. C. Greenwood, WW II (Box 56)
- Miscellaneous books and pamphlets re V. U. and other; 150th anniversary issue of Tennessean; Christmas card address file, collections, etc. (Box 57)
- Christmas cards, 1955, 1958; miscellaneous correspondence, Chapel Hill years (Box 58)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, Chapel Hill years (Box 59)
- Miscellaneous, boxes (Box 60)
- Correspondence, Ab - Ba (Box 61)
- Correspondence, Ba - Bo (Box 62)
- Correspondence, Br - Cl (Box 63)
- Correspondence, Cl - De (Box 64)
- Correspondence, De - Fo (Box 65)
- Correspondence, Fo - He (Box 66)
- Correspondence, He - Ja (Box 67)
- Correspondence, Je - Le (Box 68)
- Correspondence, Le - Me (Box 69)
- Correspondence, Me - Na (Box 70)
- Correspondence, Ne - Ph (Box 71)
- Correspondence, Pi - Ro (Box 72)
- Correspondence, Ro - So (Box 73)
- Correspondence, So - Te (Box 74)
- Correspondence, Te - Un (Box 75)
- Correspondence, Un - Wa (Box 76)
- Correspondence, Wa - Zu (Box 77)
- Reports, correspondence, etc. Am (Box 78)
- Reports, correspondence, etc. As - Ce (Box 79)
- Reports, correspondence, etc. Ce - C0 (Box 80)
- Reports, correspondence, etc. Co - Ea (Box 81)
- Reports, correspondence, etc. He - Na (Box 82)
- Reports, correspondence, etc. Na - Ro (Box 83)
- Reports, correspondence, etc. So; TIME Newstour Eastern Europe, Oct. 1981 (Box 84)
- TIME Newstour Eastern Europe, Oct. 1981; TIME Newstour Pacific Rim, Oct./Nov. 1985 (Box 85)
- TIME Newstour Pacific Rim, Oct./Nov. 1985 (Box 86)
- Ford Foundation Asia-India trip (Box 87)
- Ford Foundation Asia-India trip, Chairman's files (Box 88)
- Ford Foundation Asia-India trip, Chairman's files (Box 89)
- Ford Foundation Asia-India trip, Chairman's files (Box 90)
- Ford Foundation Asia-India trip, Chairman's files (Box 91)
- Ford Foundation Asia-India trip, Chairman's files (Box 92)
- Speech files; materials used and for possible use (Box 93)
- Speech files; materials used and for possible use (Box 94)
- Ford Foundation and TIME Incorporated (Box 95)
- Ford Foundation and TIME Incorporated; Study Commission on U.S. Policy toward Southern Africa (Box 96)
- Study Commission on U.S. Policy toward Southern Africa (Box 97)
- Ford Foundation (Box 98)
- Ford Foundation (Box 99)
- Health America, VIPPS, Sloan Foundation (Box 100)
- Health America, VIPPS, Sloan Foundation (Box 101)
- Ford Foundation; miscellaneous V. U. and other (Box 102)
- Christmas cards, 1957; Ford Foundation presidential selection study, and other materials (Box 103)
- Christmas cards, 1983; Ford Foundation presidential selection study, and other materials (Box 104)
- Speech materials, 1981-84 (Box 105)
- Speech materials, 1981-84; the correspondence (Box 106)
- The correspondence; Christmas cards, 1957; drawings, etc., for additions to 211 Deer Park Drive (Box 107)
- Ford Foundation materials; South Africa Visit, 1982; Polaroid Contingency Fund Grant (Box 108)
- Ford Foundation materials; Polaroid Contingency Fund Grant (Box 109)
- Miscellaneous; House repairs 211 Deer Park Drive; Chancellor's Council; entertainment, etc.; card file pertaining to Presidential Selection Process Project; 1962 letters of felicitation about appointment as Vanderbilt Chancellor (Box 110)
- Heard passport, Christmas cards, and other "personal" files (Box 111)
- Card file pertaining to Presidential Selection Process Project (Box 112)
- Card file pertaining to Presidential Selection Process Project; miscellaneous V. U. papers (Box 113)
- South America, 1969, 1974, 1979 (Box 114)
- World Trip (Box 115)
- Europe 1964, Jamaica, 1964, 1966 (Box 116)
- Russia, Taiwan, 1975; Europe (France) (Box 117)
- England, Ethiopia, 1973; Southeastern Asia, 1972; Iran, 1972. (Box 118)
- Ireland, Germany, Italy, 1980; Germany, 1978; Iraq, 1976 (Box 119)
- Taiwan, 1975; South Asia (Box 120)
- England, Greece, Africa (Tanzania, Congo), Egypt (Box 121)
- Japan (Box 122)
- Greece, East Africa (Box 123)
- Belgium (Box 123)
- England (Box 123)
- East Europe (Box 124)
- Europe-Israel (Box 125)
- Canada (Box 125)
- Kuwait (Box 125)
- Iran, Thailand (Box 125)
- South Africa (Box 126)
- Africa (Box 127)
- India, Japan, South Africa (Box 128)
- India (Box 129)
- Europe (Box 130)
- Europe & Egypt (Box 130)
- Germany (Box 130)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 131)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 132)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 134)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 135)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 136)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 137)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 138)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 139)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 140)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 141)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 142)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 143)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 144)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 145)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 146)
- Chapel Hill materials (Box 147)
- Miscellaneous materials (Box 148)
- Miscellaneous materials (Box 149)
  - Political Science 175 (Box 150)
  - Political Science 175 Syllabus, Fall 1956-57 (Box 150)
  - Political Science 175 Syllabus, Fall 1956-57 (Box 150)
  - Political Science 200 (Box 150)
  - Miscellaneous: Pol. Sc. 175 Notes (Box 150)
  - Political Science 175 (Box 150)
  - Election Notice (Box 150)
  - 6th Congressional District of North Carolina - Delegates & Alternatives to Democratic National Convention (Box 150)
  - Social Science Survey Course: George Simpson (Box 150)
  - Social Science II (In Manilla Envelope) (Box 150)
  - Bond Dr. (1953) Orange County (Box 150)
  - Graduate Curricullum: Dept. Comm (Box 150)
  - Baldwin, FSA (MSS) (Box 150)
  - Correspondence: To Alexander Heard from Fred H. Weaver, February 5, 1952 (Box 150)
  - Cole, Taylor (Box 150)
  - Cultural Paterns Project (Gillin) (Box 150)
  - Farm Security Adm. Study (Box 150)
  - Merchant's Addresses (Box 150)
  - Alexander Will: Money Matter (Box 150)
  - Notes/Memos to Alexander Heard (Box 150)
  - Academic Affairs Committee (Box 150)
  - Political Behavior Committee (Box 150)
  - Political Behavior Focal Area (Box 150)
  - Memorandum: To Thomas H. Carroll, Chairman, The Ford Foundation Advisory Committee From Alexander Heard, Masy 31, 1953; (Several copies) (Box 150)
  - Political Science 41 Examination, Sec. 1, June 3, 1953 (Box 150)
  - AAUP General Committee on Faculty Health Service (Box 150)
  - Institute for Research in Social Science (Box 150)
  - 49th Annual Meeting: American Political Science Association (September 10-12, 1953), Preliminary Program, Final Programs (Box 151)
  - Teacher Rating Scales (Box 151)
  - Tuck JE: Correspondence between A. Heard & Rufus C. Harris (Interlochen, Michigan - 1951) (Box 151)
  - UNC Dept. of Political Science (Box 151)
  - Orange County Record Receipts, Membership (1952-53) and Card for Young Democratic Club (1953-54) (In Manilla Envelope) (Box 151)
  - Pol. Sc.52 (Fall 1951) Course Rating Scale, Faculty Rating Booklet, Course & Instructor Evaluation Form and Pol. Sc.123 Course Evaluations, Winter 1952 (Box 151)
  - Pending: Book Orders & Inquiries (Box 151)
  - Professor York Y. Willbern (Box 151)
  - Articles re.Weapons (Box 151)
  - Planning Regional Development (Box 151)
  - Press, UNC: B. of Govs (Box 151)
  - Price, H.D (Box 151)
  - RCM: Project Y (Box 151)
  - Harris, Fred H (Box 151)
  - Sully, Tom: Honors and Suggested Reading List, October 11, 1952 (Box 151)
  - Pres. Campaign (Box 151)
  - The News & Observer (Newspaper) Raleigh, N.C., October 18, 1951 (Box 151)
  - Publications Representatives, Etc (Box 151)
  - Reading Courses: Pol. Sc.341 (Edwin Rhyne) (Box 151)
  - Requests, S peaking & Writing, Miscellaneous (Box 151)
  - Am. Pol. Sc. Assn. Roundtable (Box 151)
  - Teaching (Box 151)
  - Pol. Sci.41:Quizzes & Assignments (Box 151)
  - Pol. Sci.41 (Box 151)
  - Pol. Sci.123: Comparative Governments (Box 151)
  - Pol. Sci.123: File - Quizzes & Exam (Box 151)
  - Pol. Sci.128: Linares (Box 151)
  - Knowland TV Interview (9/28/55) and Reports by Knowland (Box 151)
  - Contributor Information (Democrat) (Box 151)
  - Empty Folder entitled, "Big Money in Little Sums" by John Van Doven (Second & Final Batch of Proofs (Box 151)
  - Empty Folder entitled, "Big Money in Little Sums" by John Van Doven (IRSS Copy Gally Proofs) (Box 151)
  - JVD Mateial (John Van Doven) Big Money in Little Sums (Publication) (Box 151)
  - A Biolgraphical Sketch - Louis R. Wilson by Maurice F. Tauber (Box 151)
  - Correspondence between A.Heard & Paul T. David re: Television Chapter, July 1955 (Box 151)
  - A.H. Book Reviews: Miscellaneous (Box 151)
  - Branscomb: Correspondence between A.Heard & Chancellor Harvie Branscomb, Vanderbilt (1952) and between A.Heard & Professor James W. Fesler, Yale (1951) and between A.Heard & Professor Alex N. Drognich, Vanderbilt (1952) and others (Box 151)
  - Book Reviews, Criticisms, Etc (Box 151)
  - Gross -2: Correspondence between A.Heard & Bertram M. Gross, Director of Research Democratic National Committee, Washington, D.C (Box 151)
  - Dem. Nat. Com: Gross (?) (Box 151)
  - Blue Green Box: A.Heard Personal (Lists, Notes, Articles, Correspondence, Lecture before the Divinity School of Duke University (given by A.Heard, Februrary 22, 1956) and Vitea of Heard (Box 151)
  - Miscellaneous (Correspondence, Text Questions, Outline of Book) (Box 151)
  - Blue Green Box: File - SSRC Pol. Beh. Comm. (Applications for Grants) (Box 152)
  - Bound Volume: Science and State Government in Connecticut (Box 152)
  - Political Science 175: Syllabus, Quiz, Supplementary Readings (Box 152)
  - Raw Computations Methodology Article (Box 152)
  - Southern Political Science Association: Gainsville, Florida (Box 152)
  - AES & South: N. Rep., November 53 (Box 152)
  - Hopkins Soc. Sci. Talk (Box 152)
  - Jonathan Daniels TV Program (Box 152)
  - Political Science 128: Lecture Notes by Visiting Professor Dr. Linares Quintana (Box 152)
  - Political Science 175: Term Papers (Box 152)
  - Political Science 200, Spring 1954 (Box 152)
  - Political Science 341: Collegial Seminar, Spring 1956; (Notebook: C. B. Robson) (Box 152)
  - Outline of Books (Box 152)
  - Political Science 200, "The History, Scope & Method of Political Science" (Fall 1956) Notebook (Box 152)
  - Term Paper (M. Laulan) (Box 152)
  - Political Science 200, "The History, Scope & Method of Political Science" Syllabus and Related Papers, Spring Sem. 1956 (Box 152)
  - Chi Omega Article (Box 152)
  - Young Democratic Clubs of North Carolina, 1951-53 (Box 152)
  - The News & Observer (Newspaper) Raleigh, North Carolina, November 28, 1956 (Box 152)
  - Precinct 4 (Box 152)
  - Carrboro Precinct (Box 152)
  - YDC: Orange Co., ?/3/54 (Box 152)
  - U.S.Senate Subcommittee on Privileges & Elections, November 2, 1956 (Box 153)
  - Lists of Contributions of $10,000 or more (A.Heard is the folder name) (Box 153)
  - The Economist, August 15, 1956 (Box 153)
  - Plan for a Study of Money in American Politics: UNC - Institute for Research in Social Science (Box 153)
  - Publication: A Long-Range Plan for the City University of New York, 1961-1975 (Box 153)
  - Money and Politics (Public Affairs Pamphlet) by Alexander Heard (Box 153)
  - Assorted Pamphlets (Box 153)
  - Publication: Concerts 1958-59, UNC Department of Music (Box 153)
  - Tennessee Interviews: Folder #1 (Box 153)
  - Mississippi: Interviews: Number One (Box 153)
  - Report of the Trustees of the Ford Foundation, September 27, 1950 (Box 153)
  - The Oliver Max Gardner Award (1956) and Dinner Program (Box 153)
  - Publication: Excerpts from the Cresap, McCormick & Paget Management Study Report, 1953? (Box 153)
  - The President's Report (UNC): 1948-53, 1953-54, 1954-55, 1958-59, 1959-60 & 1960-61 (Box 153)
  - Visiting Committee Report: Survey of the Behavioral Sciences (1953-54), UNC (Box 153)
  - AAUP Bulletin (June 1962) Summer Issue (Box 153)
  - Interim Report, Office of Researach Administration (May ll, 1962 [1961-61]) and Expenditures of Federal Funds at the University of Rochester, 5 Year Summary, May 9, 1962 (Box 153)
  - Congressional Districts for the 88th Congress May, to July 1, 1962 (Box 153)
  - University of Rochester Investment Report (Rochester, New York), January 1, 19962 (Box 153)
  - Publication: Public Administration Review, (Winter 1959, Vol. XIX, Num. 1) (Box 153)
  - The Library of Congress Legislative Reference Service: Preferential Presidential Primaries by Mollie Z. Margolin, June 15, 1961 (Box 153)
  - E.P.S. Confidential Memoranda (Box 154)
  - Arkansas Interviews: Folder #1 (Box 154)
  - St. Simon's Article (Box 154)
  - Transfer: Miscellaneous (1958-61) G, H, I, J, K (Box 154)
  - Transfer: Miscellaneous (1958-61) P, Q, R (Box 154)
  - Miscellaneous (Desegregation Pamphlets, Journal Articles, Oral Examination in Pol. Sci., Etc.) (Box 154)
  - General: Association of Graduate Schools, 1958-61 (Box 154)
  - Three Year Report: Indian Health Education Training Project, July 1955 - July 1958 (Box 154)
  - Pamphlet: "Toward Higher Ground" (175th Anniversary of Founding of University of Pittsburg) (Box 154)
  - Rreport: "The University in the Life of the State" (Box 154)
  - UNC: Department of Political Science, 1958-61 (Box 154)
  - Fifth World Congress: International Political Science Association - Paris, September 26-30, 1961 (Box 154)
  - Political Participation Study (Box 154)
  - Six Packages of Christmas Cards Received (Box 155)
  - Miscellaneous Periodicals (Box 156)
  - Journal: Arms Control Today, 1984 -1991, not fully complete (Box 157)
  - Party Lists (Box 157)
  - AAU, Vanderbilt University Entertainment Programs/Brochures and Party Lists (Box 157)
  - Heard's Personal Lists and Invitations (Box 157)
  - Action File (Correspondence Lists, Repairs for Organ, Etc.) (Box 157)
  - Nashville Institute for the Arts (Jean Heard) (Box 157)
  - Personal Correspondence, (Invitations, Ceremonies, Marriages, Etc.) (Box 157)
  - Bound Volume: Tort Law and the Public Interest by Peter H. Schuck, ed (Box 157)
  - Journal: The Annals of the American Academy of Political & Social Science, May 1993 (Box 157)
  - Report: "Science, Technology, & Government for a Changing World, Carnegie Comission, April 1993 (Box 157)
  - Annual Report: The Robert A. Taft Institute of Government (Box 157)
  - Bound Volume: The Visit by Friedrich Durrenmatt (Box 158)
  - Bound Volume: Sophocles I (Box 158)
  - LIFE excerpt: "Queen of Cathedrals", December 15, 1961 (Box 158)
  - Alexander & Jean Heard's Itinerary: Destination - Yellowstone & Grand Teton National Parks (July 8-August 13, 1977) (Includes 2 Maps: Eastern U.S. & Central & Western U.S. and Miscell.) (Box 158)
  - Communications (Box 158)
  - General: Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies (Box 158)
  - Growth Values, Etc (Box 158)
  - Heard: Income Tax Papers, 1960, 1962, 1963 (Box 158)
  - Lousiana Interviews: Folder #1 (Box 158)
  - North Carolina Interviews: Number One (Box 158)
  - Florida: Folder #1 (Box 158)
  - Georgia Interviews: Number One - Index (Box 158)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 158)
  - Pol. Sci.52: Exam (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci.52: Short Quizes & Hour Quiz on U.S.S.R (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Assignment Sheets (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Labour & Industry in Britian (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - ?; Sp. Throne (?) (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Quiz 1 (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Quiz 2 (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Quiz 3 (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Quiz 4 (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Hour Quiz (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: France - Quiz 5 (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: France - Quiz 6 (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: France - Hour Quiz (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Germany - Quiz (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 54: Scandinavian Government (J. Roberts) (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Bibliography (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Notes (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Notes #2 (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Gen. Elec. (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Gen. Cab. Syst. (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Pub. (Box 159)
  - Policies (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Labour Party (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain - Empire Rels. (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: France - Notes (Box 159)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Germany - Notes (Box 159)
  - This Week Magazine, Des Moines Sunday Register, July 14, 1963 (Box 159)
  - Local Political Surveys by E.E.Schattschneider & Victor Jones (Box 159)
  - "Preliminary Report of an Inquiry Into the Length of Doctoral Programs: Survey of Recent Doctoral Graduates", November 1960 (Box 159)
  - Journal: Case Studies in Practical Politics (16 volumes) (Box 159)
  - Journal: Public Administration Review, Summer 1960 (Box 159)
  - University of North Carolina: President's Report, 1953-54 & 1954-55 (Box 159)
  - Department of State: Interview Report No.25, "Aboard A Soviet Freighter", August 1960 (Box 159)
  - Publication: Some Dilemas in Graduate Education by John C. Weaver, University of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska (Box 159)
  - Journal: The American Behavioral Scientist, April 1962, Vol.V, No.8 (Box 159)
  - The Fund for the Republic (3-Year Report), May 31, 1959 (Box 159)
  - Texas Interviews (Box 159)
  - "Graduate Education In the U.S." by Bernard Berelson, University of Chicago, January 1960 (Box 159)
  - Professional Correspondence (Various Departments of State, Etc.) (Box 160)
  - Pol.Sci. D01 (Pol. Sci. 200) - "The Study of Political Science", Northwestern University (Fall 1955) Mr. Hyneman, Instructor (Box 160)
  - Pol. Sci. 200 (Box 160)
  - 2.0 (Continued) (Box 160)
  - Scope: Methodology (Box 160)
  - Pol. Sci. 200: Term Paper, November 13, 1958 (Box 160)
  - Joseph H. Willits (Box 160)
  - Poll Tax Study (Recommendations for Members of Commission) (Box 160)
  - Poll Tax Study (New Stories & Editorial Comment) (Box 160)
  - Poll Tax Study (New Stories & Editorial Comment from Governor Arnall's File) (Box 160)
  - HLP King Envelopes returned by S. H. Collection (Alexander Heard) (Box 160)
  - Letters from Editors on the Poll Tax (Box 160)
  - Poll Tax Study (Who's Who Write-Ups on Men Recommended for Commission) (Box 160)
  - KWT Hangover Chores, Etc (Box 160)
  - Interviews: Inadvertently Omitted (Manilla Envelope) (Box 160)
  - Assorted Publications (The Election Law (1950), Arkansas Election Laws (1950, Etc.) (Box 160)
  - 1948 Christmas Cards (Box 160)
  - Aviation Maps & Papers (Includes 2 Flight Plotting Instruments) (Box 160)
  - Aviation (Pilot) Publications & Manuals (Box 160)
  - Publication: A Century of Books (Box 160)
  - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 160)
  - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 161)
  - Duke Talk Response (Box 162)
  - Report of the Special Committee on the Presidency (American Association of University Professors) UNC, November 28, 1955; (41 copies) (Box 162)
  - Disc (Recording) Envelopes (Box 162)
  - UNC Miscellaneous (Pol. Sci. 200 [Spring 1956] Course Papers, Letters, Proposals, Surveys) (Box 162)
  - Pol. Sci. 341 (1956) Folder (Box 162)
  - Pol. Sci. 341 (1956) Loose Leaf Papers (Box 162)
  - Travel Timetables [Railroad, Air] (1950-53) (Includes Notes re: Eastern Air Lines - CH (Chapel Hill?) to NYC (9/25/52) and Airline Timetables (Box 162)
  - North Carolina Maps (Box 162)
  - Working Manuscript for "A Study of Money in American Politics" (UNC) (Box 162)
  - President's Commission on Campaign Costs (CCC) (John F. Kennedy) (Box 163)
  - Assorted Newspaper Clippings (Box 163)
  - 3 Black 3-Ring Notebooks of Newspaper Clippints (Box 163)
  - 4 Green 3-Ring Notebooks of Records, Letters, Etc (Box 163)
  - Journal: The Progressive (July 1962) and Journal: U.S.News & World Report, May 28, 1962 (Box 163)
  - Miscellaneous Papers & Reports re: CCC (Box 163)
  - JFK Corresondence (Alexander Heard & John F. Kennedy) (Box 163)
  - Political Sciene 200: Seminar Papers (Box 164)
  - Student Registration, 1952-53 (Box 164)
  - Political Behavior Summer Seminar Group (Cole) (Box 164)
  - Seminar Action Material (Box 164)
  - Political Statistics: Truman & SSRC (Box 164)
  - SSRC: Political Statistics Project (Box 164)
  - A Proposal to Conduct a Study of MONEY IN POLITICS by Alexander Heard, Department of Political Science and Institute for Research in Social Science, February 1953 (Box 164)